Ammar Sahyoun

Veberöd-Sweden



ammarzgr@hotmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ammar-sahyoun



0046 739 714925



https://ammarsahyoun.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

I am a passionate programmer with good analytics skills that have two years of experience in web development, I did Yrkeshögskoleexamen 2020 along with 4 months intern in Sogeti/Malmö as a Data Engineer where I was one of the analytics team that developed AI / Geo solutions.

I also took apart a part-time job with internal financial data by extracting it from API, transform it to SQL/NoSQL and upload it in BigQuery or send it as a spreadsheet report.

I have also experienced working in various Business Intelligence tools for data visualization where I used Power BI to spot the relation between data association and deliver it as interactive reports

Currently, I am seeking to use my proven skills in Python, Java, and SQL/NoSQL to help you tackle your business problems.

Personally, I'm structured, focused, and likes taking on new challenges but is also humble and a problem solver willing to do what it takes to get a job done. I always focus on the project deliverables and looking for continuous improvement.

Experience



Data Engineer

Sogeti

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020 (5 months)

As a Data Engineer, I used the GIS techniques that helped me in the ETL, to extract data from the satellite image according to exact fields and transform it into another form and create indicators to make data analysis. my contribution was to prepare a project for the Swedish Agriculture authority, by automating a pipeline that download, extract, transform and calculate the indicator values in time series analysis to help to fit a classification model for crop monitoring.



Data Engineer

Nvrmind-Part time

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021 (2 months)

Set up serverless functions in GCP as part of CI/CD pipeline, the functions retrieve the inner data from API's, transform and upload that data to tables in BigQuery, or tabs in google Worksheets.



Maintenance Technician

Nokia

Mar 2003 - Nov 2011 (8 years 9 months)

I have Performed testing tuning and maintenance of electronic circuits via signal generator, GSM tester, signal analyzer and oscilloscope. I have good experience in electronics soldering, troubleshooting and electronics schematics.

Education



Lexicon Malmö AB

IT-säkerhet May 2021 - Sep 2021 Python, SQL, Django, Cybersecurity



Komvux Lund

Grundläggande nivå, Svenska som andra språk Jan 2021 - Jun 2021 Svenska Grundläggande, Engelska 5

Handelsakademin

Yrkeshögskoleexamen, Object-oriented programming and Al 2019 - 2020

Part of the course was object-oriented programming in (Html, CSS, Javascript), Java and working in practical projects with different relational databases.

The second part of the course deals with AI and data analysis, ML, ANN, TensorFlow, AWS deployment.

Damascus University

Bachelor, Electronics Engineer - Control 1995 - 1998

I have studied basic electronics and practised in lab studies on circuit design, programming and control systems.

Licenses & Certifications



🔼 Introduction to TensorFlow - Google Cloud - Minnesota

MNEX3LUS3VQG

Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra-Imperial College London -

Coursera Course Certificates 4Y876TBJPZ5L



Linux Server Management and Security - University of Colorado

M7NFN6CYM6FD



Interactivity with JavaScript - University of Michigan

BCXEAU484ABQ

- Object-Oriented Design University of Alberta ET2HE4SP7PSS
- Database Management Essentials Coursera
 6KF2M4X2ENBQ
- Python for Data Science and AI Coursera 78Z4SNBG9CLM
- Object Detection with AWS Sagemaker- Guided Project Amazon Web Services (AWS)

 MCGL3B47GMLF
- IBM -Data Analysis with Python Coursera
- Google cloud Launching into Machine Learning Google Cloud Minnesota Z6KPR7YM2TXD
- GIS Data Formats, Design and Quality University of California, Davis GEQG828NRVVZ

Skills

Python • SQL • Java • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Data Analysis • Data Science • Spatial analysis • Linux Server • Microsoft Power BI • Extract, Transform, Load (ETL)